carbonfund.org 2019-12-30

# Privacy Policy Donor Information - Carbonfund.org Foundation

## Our Commitment to Our Donors

We will not sell, share or trade our donors’ names or personal information with any other entity, nor send mailings to our donors on behalf of other organizations.

This policy applies to all information received by Carbonfund.org Foundation, both online and offline, on any Platform (“Platform”, includes the Carbonfund.org Foundation website and mobile applications), as well as any electronic, written, or oral communications.

To the extent any donations are processed through a third-party service provider, our donors’ information will only be used for purposes necessary to process the donation.

The following statement details the Carbonfund.org Foundation, Inc. privacy policy. You may also be interested in our [ **Terms of Use**](https://carbonfund.org/terms-of-use/). If you have any questions, please [ **contact us**](https://carbonfund.org/contact/).

### What personal information is collected and how is it used?

No personally identifiable data is collected from individuals through this website, unless this information is given by you in regards to online donations.

Online donations are secure. When you make a donation we will collect the following information in order to process the order: name, address, phone number, email address and credit card information. If you are making a donation on behalf of someone else, we will collect their name, address, and email address if provided. We use your information to process your donation and to verify credit card data. We use your mailing address to send your certificate, if ordered, and to let you know about our projects through our publications. Your phone number is used only to contact you if we need to verify order information and occasionally to thank you for your contribution. We do not share your phone number with telemarketing centers. Your email address may be used to contact you regarding your donation or to let you know about our projects. The recipient’s names and addresses are used in similar manner, to send the certificate to them and to inform them of Carbonfund.org projects.

Carbonfund.org respects your privacy and will discontinue contacting you at your request, either written or oral.

We do not share your personal information with any other organization, except for a third-party financial institution to process credit cards. The information sent to them is only to verify credit card numbers and process the order in a secure environment. We do not rent or share our mailing list. If you give a donation via one our partnerships, then your personal information is shared with the sponsoring partner and the third-party financial institution to process the credit card.

### Is this information secure?

When persons visit our site, data collected by our computers will not be publicly displayed. It is used for our internal data collection purposes only, and is held by our server in a secure location. Our donation and shopping area uses secure web pages when your credit card information is collected. Our online credit card processing system is handled by a third party. Information is relayed to them through secure channels using SSL (Secure Sockets Layer).

### What other types of information are collected, and how are they used?

#### Cookies

Carbonfund.org uses “cookie” messages to automatically help provide better services. They remind us who you are and how you like to use our web site, based on what you’ve done and told us before. The “cookie” is placed in your computer and is read when you come back to our web site. Cookies let us take you to the information and features you’re particularly interested in. They also let us track your and others’ usage, so we know which parts of our sites are most popular. You can reject cookies or very easily cancel them later. If you would like your browser to reject cookies, you can instruct your browser to do so although some features might become unavailable.

#### Aggregate information

When guests enter our site, our server picks up information used to help us provide our users with better services and for internal record keeping. This information is picked up automatically from your Internet Service Provider and web browser, and includes your type of computer operating system and the browser that you are using, IP addresses, and demographic data. Also collected is the number of people viewing our web site. This information is collected in non-identifiable form.

#### What if a person has questions about the privacy of this site?

It is our hope that you enjoy and feel comfortable exploring our web site. If you feel that we are not abiding by our posted privacy policy in any respect, please immediately contact us via mail at 853 Main Street East Aurora, NY 14052 or via email at [info@carbonfund.org](mailto:info@carbonfund.org).

What happens when our privacy policy is updated? We may update our web site or make changes in our procedure, which may require an update to our privacy policy. This change would appear in our posted policy and your continued usage of our site would indicate agreement and compliance with this new policy.
